harm.
And this was sung every Sunday morning after the hoisting of the flag.
But somehow, neither the words nor the tune ever seemed to the animals to come
up to Beasts of England.
Chapter 8
A few days later, when the terror caused by the executions had died down,
some of the animals remembered, or thought they remembered, that the Sixth
Commandment decreed No animal shall kill any other animal.
And though no one cared to mention it in the hearing of the pigs or the dogs,
it was felt that the killings which had taken place did not square with this.
Clover asked Benjamin to read her the Sixth Commandment, and when Benjamin, as
usual, said that he refused to meddle in such matters, she fetched Muriel.
Muriel read the Commandment for her. It ran No animal shall kill any other animal without cause.
Somehow or other, the last two words had slipped out of the animals' memory.
But they saw now that the commandment had not been violated.
For clearly there was good reason for killing the traitors who had leagued
themselves with Snowball.
Throughout the year, the animals worked even harder than they had worked in the previous year.
To rebuild the windmill with walls twice as thick as before, and to finish it by
the appointed date, together with the regular work of the farm, was a tremendous labor.
There were times when it seemed to the animals that they worked longer hours
and fared no better than they had done in Jones's day.
On Sunday mornings, Squealer, holding down a long strip of paper with his trotter,
would read out to them lists of figures proving that the production of every
class of foodstuff had increased by 200%, 300%, or 500%, as the case might be.
The animals saw no reason to disbelieve him, especially as they could no longer
remember very clearly what conditions had been like before the rebellion.
All the same, there were days when they felt that they would sooner have had
less figures and more food.
All orders were now issued through Squealer or one of the other pigs.
Napoleon himself was not seen in public as often as once in a fortnight.
When he did appear, he was attended not only by his retinue of dogs, but by a
black cockerel who marched in front of him and acted as a kind of trumpeter,
letting out a loud "Cock-a-doodle-doo!"
before Napoleon spoke.
Even in the farmhouse, it was said, Napoleon inhabited separate apartments from the others.
He took his meals alone, with two dogs to wait upon him,
and always ate from the Crown Derby dinner service, which had been in the
glass cupboard in the drawing room.
It was also announced that the gun would be fired every year on Napoleon's birthday
as well as on the other two anniversaries.
Napoleon was now never spoken of simply as Napoleon.
He was always referred to in formal style as our leader, Comrade Napoleon.
And the pigs liked to invent for him such titles as father of all animals, terror of mankind,
protector of the sheepfold, ducklings' friend, and the like.
In his speeches, Squealer would talk with the tears rolling down his cheeks
of Napoleon's wisdom, the goodness of his heart, and the deep love he bore to all animals
everywhere, even and especially the unhappy animals who still lived in ignorance and slavery
on other farms.
It had become usual to give Napoleon the credit for every successful achievement
and every stroke of good fortune.
You would often hear one hen remark to another, >> "Under the guidance of our leader,
Comrade Napoleon, I have laid five eggs in six days."
>> Or two cows enjoying a drink at the pool would exclaim,
>> "Thanks to the leadership of Comrade Napoleon, how excellent this water tastes."
>> The general feeling on the farm was well expressed in a poem entitled Comrade
Napoleon, which was composed by Minimus and which ran as follows.
>> Friend of the fatherless, fountain of happiness, lord of the swill bucket. Oh,
how my soul is on fire when I gaze at thy calm and commanding eye. Like the
sun in the sky, Comrade Napoleon, thou art the giver of all that thy creatures love.
Full belly twice a day, clean straw to roll upon, every beast, great or small, sleeps at
peace in his stall.
Thou watchest over all, Comrade Napoleon.
Had I a sucking pig ere he had grown as
big even as a pint bottle or as a rolling pin, he should have learned to
be faithful and true to thee. Yes, his first squeak should be Comrade Napoleon.
>> Napoleon approved of this poem and caused it to be inscribed on the wall of
the big barn at the opposite end from the seven commandments.
It was surmounted by a portrait of Napoleon in profile, executed by Squealer in white paint.
Meanwhile, through the agency of Whymper, Napoleon was engaged in
complicated negotiations with Frederick and Pilkington.
The pile of timber was still unsold.
Of the two, Frederick was the more anxious to get hold of it,
but he would not offer a reasonable price.
At the same time, there were renewed rumors that Frederick and his men were
plotting to attack Animal Farm and to destroy the windmill, the building of which had aroused
furious jealousy in him.
Snowball was known to be still skulking on Pinchfield Farm.
In the middle of the summer, the animals were alarmed to hear that three hens had
come forward and confessed that, inspired by Snowball, they had entered
into a plot to murder Napoleon.
They were executed immediately, and fresh precautions for Napoleon's safety were taken.
Four dogs guarded his bed at night, one at each corner,
and a young pig named Pinkeye was given the task of tasting all his food before
he ate it, lest it should be poisoned.
At about the same time, it was given out that Napoleon had arranged to sell the
pile of timber to Mr. Pilkington.
He was also going to enter into a regular agreement for the exchange of
certain products between Animal Farm and Foxwood.
The relations between Napoleon and Pilkington, though they were only
conducted through Whymper, were now almost friendly.
The animals distrusted Pilkington as a human being, but greatly preferred him
to Frederick, whom they both feared and hated.
As the summer wore on and the windmill neared completion, the rumors of an
impending treacherous attack grew stronger and stronger.
Frederick, it was said, intended to bring against them 20 men all armed with
guns, and he had already bribed the magistrates and police so that if he
could once get hold of the title deeds of Animal Farm, they would ask no questions.
Moreover, terrible stories were leaking out from Pinchfield about the cruelties that
Frederick practiced upon his animals.
He had flogged an old horse to death. He starved his cows. He had killed a dog by
throwing it into the furnace.
He amused himself in the evenings by making fight with splinters of
razor blade tied to their spurs.
The animals' blood boiled with rage when they heard of these things being done to
their comrades, and sometimes they clamored to be allowed to go out in a body and attack
Pinchfield Farm, drive out the humans, and set the animals free.
But Squealer counseled them to avoid rash actions and trust in Comrade Napoleon's strategy.
Nevertheless, feeling against Frederick continued to run high.
One Sunday morning, Napoleon appeared in the barn and explained that he had never
at any time contemplated selling the pile of timber to Frederick.
He considered it beneath his dignity, he said, to have dealings with scoundrels
of that description.
The pigeons, who were still sent out to spread tidings of the rebellion, were
forbidden to set foot anywhere on Foxwood, and were also ordered to drop
their former slogan of death to humanity in favor of death to Frederick.
In the late summer, yet another of Snowball's machinations was laid bare.
The wheat crop was full of weeds, and it was discovered that on one of his
nocturnal visits, Snowball had mixed weed seeds with the seed corn.
A gander, who had been privy to the plot, had confessed his guilt to
Squealer and immediately committed suicide by swallowing deadly nightshade berries.
The animals now also learned that Snowball had never, as many of them had
believed hitherto, received the order of Animal Hero First Class.
This was merely a legend which had been spread sometime after the Battle of the
Cowshed by Snowball himself.
So far from being decorated, he had been